# Swara Snehal Gandhi

🔀 swaragandhi5@gmail.com 📞 +12265052350 🔮 Waterloo, Canada

in www.linkedin.com/in/swara-gandhi-901028207 https://github.com/swaragandhi5

Data Scientist and University of Waterloo graduate with an specialization in Artificial Intelligence and Machine learning and hands on experience with data science projects. I help companies to solve business problems and uncover insights through predictive modelling, data processing, data mining algorithms and tools like Power BI and Tableau

## **Education**

University of Waterloo

## Master's in Electrical and Computer Engineering | GPA: 3.25,

05/2021 - 08/2022

- Specialization in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning and Diploma certification in Business Entrepreneurship.
- Relevant Coursework: Data preprocessing, Data Classification, Machine Learning algorithms, Neural Networks, Algorithm Design and Analysis, Introduction to Optimization, Embodied Intelligence.

## Bachelor's in Computer Engineering | CGPA: 8.86,

09/2015 - 05/2019

Gujarat Technological University

• Relevant Coursework: Programming Languages, Data Structures, Algorithms, Database management system, SQL, Computer Architecture, Computer Networks.

# **Professional Experience**

## Software Engineer | Ashario - Toronto, ON

11/2022 – present

- Ranked Ashario stores in top 10 results by optimizing online visibility and performing Search Engine Optimization techniques using Google analytics and insights from various SEO techniques.
- Implementing WordPress website for the firm to increase the revenue on WordPress using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Increased revenue by providing price monitoring insights through Web scraping in Python and beautiful Soup 4.

## iOS Application Developer Intern | Cloud Web Technologies - India

05/2018 - 06/2019

- Developed and designed iOS mobile shopping app for a clothing brand named Shubhlaxmi.
- Implemented interactive features to improve user experience.
- Tech Stack: Swift, XCode, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL.

## **Skills**

## **Data Analysis:**

Data visualization, Reports and Dashboard creation using Power BI, SQL, Data cleaning and Exploratory data analysis, Statistical analysis, Matplotlib and Seaborn

#### **Programming:**

C, C++, Java, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Swift

## **Machine Learning:**

Python, Natural Language Processing, Neural Networks, Regression, Classification, Clustering, dimensionality reduction, ensemble methods.

#### Familiarity with

ETL Pipeline, PostgreSQL, Git, PHP, .NET, Software development lifecycle, Agile methodology

# **Projects**

#### **Sentiment Analysis**

- Increased accuracy to 88% by implementing Feed Forward Neural Network model to predict polarity of 50,000 IMDB movie reviews.
- Performed natural language processing based Tokenization, lemmatization, vectorization and cleaned data in machine understandable language.
- Model includes Keras, LSTM and dropout units with Adam optimizer.

## Prediction of COVID-19 cases

- Predicted Active, Confirmed and death cases with 88% testing accuracy for 2019 kaggle COVID 19 dataset.
- Machine Learning techniques like Data Cleaning, Preprocessing and Prediction using Pandas and NumPy.
- Used Ensemble methods such as KNN(supervised learning classifier), Random Forest, Naïve Bayes in sklearn and

## Different levels of embodiment on Braitenberg vehicle

- Intelligent robot simulated in Webots (Open source robot simulator) was made to interact with the environment and track the behavior.
- Python GUI toolkit Tkinter was used to simulate the actions of Braitenberg vehicle to track collision avoidance in various scenarios with variety of environmental complexities and stimuli.

#### **Courses**

# Power BI Essential Training (2020) - LinkedIn Learning